KARTHIK KAIPLODY

<u>KarthikKaiplody.github.io</u> | +13122167349 | Karthik.Kaiplody@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/KarthikKaiplody

SUMMARY

Machine Learning Engineer who designed and implemented microservice architectures for Data Science products using AWS and Serverless framework reducing the resources costs to 30%. Deployed MLOps pipeline using infrastructure as a code, methodology to minimize the model turnaround time from a week to few hours, having prior experience in Networking, FinTech, Insurance domains. Presently pursuing my Master's in Data Science from Illinois Tech.

Chicago, IL

Bangalore

Davangere

EDUCATION

Illinois Institute of Technology

Master's in Data Science August 2022 - Spring 2024

International Institute of Information Technology

Post Graduate Diploma in Machine Learning (ML) and AI. March 2020 - Apr 2021

GM Institute of Technology (Visvesvaraya Technological University)

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Sept 2012 – July 2016

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGY STACK: AWS, Python, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, NLTK, spaCy, Flask, Git, Gitlab, SQL, PostgreSQL, PyCaret, MLFlow, Docker, Digital Ocean.

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS: Teamwork, Collaborative, Logical Thinking, Client Management, Interpersonal Communication

CORE SKILLS: Data pipeline development and deployment, Natural language Processing Techniques, Object Oriented Programming(Oops), State-of-Art Deep Learning models, Feature selection Techniques, Machine learning algorithms, Statistical Testing, Image Processing, Data Visualization, Computer Vision, SVM, XGBoost, CNN/RNN family, Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment(CI/CD), MLOps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CCC Intelligent Solutions, Chicago

Data Science Enginer R&D Intern | May 2023 to Present

- Designed and built a CI/CD pipeline for AI products.
- Worked on AWS migration of machine learning models and packages.

Scalable Computing Software (SCS) Laboratory, Illinois Institute of Technology

Research Assistant | Feb 2023 to May 2023

- Creating onboarding tool for the nutritional data.
- Worked on designing the end to end machine learning pipeline.

Acuity Knowledge Partners LTD

Machine Learning Engineer - III | Aug 2021 to Aug 2022

- Deployed transformer-based models into the production pipeline using MLOps best practices.
- Completed serverless architecture using AWS Lambda functions and redesigned it as a micro-service architecture.
- Implemented AWS Step-function workflow to automate and monitor the data engineering pipeline.

Mindtree Ltd

Senior Engineer, ER&D | Aug 2017 to Aug 2021

- Introduced the pipeline to perform ETL operations on the documents from different external databases.
- Developed BERT and ELMO-based embeddings for NLP classifiers which helped in increasing the accuracy to 83%.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND ACCOLADES

- BEAT Innovation Day Challenge 2022 at Acuity Knowledge Partners Ltd Awarded 1st prize for the SPAC Datahub product.
- Kaggle Competition, TPS Jan 2021 Finished top 29% of the leader board
- Hacker Earth Deep Learning Challenge Got 110th rank out of 3363 people who participated
- Real-time Wireless Electrocardiogram and Its signal Display -Awarded as "Project of the Year" from Karnataka State Council for Science and Technology & IISc, Bangalore

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS MACHINE LEARNING FOUNDATIONS (AWS)
- Fine Tune BERT for Text Classification with TensorFlow (Coursera)
- Transfer learning for NLP with TensorFlow Hub (Coursera)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Restaurant Finder Chatbot on slack Developed a restaurant -search chatbot with the help of RASA framework and deployed it in Slack
- Bank Note Authentication Prediction Developed a Flask app which predicts whether the bank note is authentic or not based on independent values provided.